<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Vision on Omar Abid</title>
    <link>https://omarabid59.github.io/tags/computer-vision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Vision on Omar Abid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://omarabid59.github.io/tags/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Assistant</title>
      <link>https://omarabid59.github.io/activities/research_assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omarabid59.github.io/activities/research_assistant/</guid>
      <description>Research Assistant at York University Active and Attentive Vision Lab Supervisor: John K. Tsotsos Description&amp;ldquo;: Addition of new features to TarzaNN – a neural network simulator. Implemented in C++. Report can be found here.
Electrophysiology Lab (October 2013 - April 2014) Supervisor: Roger Lewis Description&amp;ldquo;: Design and development of an electronic circuit for current-voltage measurements of Neurospora crassa hyphae. Report can be found here.
Attention Learning Lab (April 2013 - August 2014) Supervisor: Thilo Womelsdorf Description&amp;ldquo;: Statistical EEG Data analysis of Macaque Monkeys for neural population decoding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attentional Control Signals, Poster Publication</title>
      <link>https://omarabid59.github.io/projects/attention_control_signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omarabid59.github.io/projects/attention_control_signals/</guid>
      <description>Publication: R. Sengupta, O. Abid, A. Bachoo, J.K. Tsotsos 2017. Attentional blink as a product of attentional control signals: A computational investigation, VSS 2017. [Link]. Implemented in C++ with TarzaNN framework. A video demonstration shows the GUI of the system processing a stream of input letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision based hand mouse cursor system</title>
      <link>https://omarabid59.github.io/projects/hci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omarabid59.github.io/projects/hci/</guid>
      <description>Instructor: Scott MacKenzie
Design and implementation of a hand tracking and hand gesture classification system used to demonstrate it’s capability as an adjunct to a computer mouse. Link. Used several technologies for its implementation in Matlab:
 Image Processing Algorithms: Color segmentation, Background subtraction, Histogram of Gradient (HOG) feature extraction
 Hand Tracking Algorithm: Kalman Filter
 Real time Gesture Classification using Matlab’s Neural Network Toolbox  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Work</title>
      <link>https://omarabid59.github.io/projects/course_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omarabid59.github.io/projects/course_work/</guid>
      <description>Distributed Computing Instructor: Eric Rupert
Description: Distributed computing is the study of how distributed networked computers pass messages, coordinate their actions. Such systems provide improved reliability and efficiency. Topics include GPU programming, synchronous and asynchronous systems, and computational complexity theory. Below you will find several assignments that were completed when taking this course.
 Two Generals Problem (Assignment, Solution) Asynchronous Processes (Assignment, Solution) Byzantine Failures (Assignment, Solution) K-set Consensus Problem (Assignment, Solution) Shared Memory System (Assignment, Solution)  Computer Vision Algorithm Comparison Instructor: Minas Setsakis Description: Test a variety of different feature extraction algorithms on real world images.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>